Caibao,
have you finished your proposal?
N-no.
I... I'm too tired.
I'm just stretching a bit.
I'll get to it right away.
Caibao.
Wei,
let me help you.
Just say what you want to say.
Wei,
lately, our team's
atmosphere has been too oppressive
and suffocating.
My weak and helpless heart
really can't take it.
Ask yourself,
is my proposal really that bad?
Not really.
Then do you think his proposal is better than mine?
It actually is.
Wei,
to be honest,
we finally managed
to get into flight control.
We got a task as soon as we came in,
and there are so many eyes on us now.
We have to deliver on this, don't we?
I know.
I...
Wei,
I know you want to do better,
but we also have to act according to our capabilities, right?
Yes, Qi's attitude is very negative,
but he has a point.
Even the best ideas have to be put into practice.
Taking a step back,
no matter whose proposal we use in the end,
shouldn't we unite to do it well?
You came from Mr. Zhao's side.
If you go back in disgrace,
how embarrassing would that be?
Can you let me finish first?
Okay, you speak.
I just think...
Where was I?
It doesn't matter.
I know what you mean.
I won't argue with him anymore.
I also know I have many shortcomings.
Just like everyone else,
I hope the flight simulation will be a success.
I know what's important.
I will cooperate with the team. Don't worry.
That's right.
That's my good brother Wei.
Just like that, your perspective broadens.
Shadow Fiend Vanguard.
Jia,
I actually...
Have you finished your proposals?
Not yet.
Then why are you chatting? Hurry up and get to work.
Caibao, you too.
Go. Go. Go.
Son.
Uncle, Aunt.
Hello.
Please come in.
Qi,
Mom and Dad came to see you.
Is this your roommate?
Auntie, I'm Wu Wei.
From the Hangda family courtyard.
It's been too long, you probably don't remember.
Wu Wei, I remember.
You ate at our house when you were little.
Then you moved, right?
Yes.
That's wonderful. You've both grown so much.
You were good friends when you were little.
Now you are roommates.
It must be fate.
Auntie, I'll leave you two to talk.
All right.
You go ahead.
You haven't been home for so long.
Mom and Dad had to come see you.
Are you used to the dorm?
Do you have to work overtime?
How's the food in the cafeteria?
Tell me all about it.
Son, do you have any plans?
What plans?
For the future, of course.
Listen to me.
Career planning is crucial.
Are you going to be a professional
or take the administrative route?
Knowing when and how to do it
is very important.
I'm telling you, it's like playing chess.
You have to think three steps ahead.
I've looked into it for you.
In the aerospace system,
the youngest chief designer
was appointed at the age of 30.
You're 25 this year
and you don't have a PhD.
So you have to hurry.
No matter what, in your first year,
you have to get the professional title.
I haven't thought about that.
How can you not, son?
He who gives no thought to the future is sure to be beset by worries at hand.
I'm telling you.
You're my son.
I will support whatever you do.
But how you will develop in the future,
you have to know what you want.
You have to set a big goal now.
Then you can move forward step by step
and climb up.
You can't do stupid things.
You can't just immerse yourself in tasks all day
and make no progress.
All those who can enter the aerospace system
and flight control
are one in a million.
Once you enter the unit,
everyone is on the same starting line.
But what about five years later?
Ten years later?
How many can become chief designers?
How many can become academicians?
The gap will be huge.
Most people
work hard their whole lives
and just end up as a subordinate.
Mom.
Do you remember the Math Olympiad when I was little?
I got second place nationwide.
You threw away my medal
and hit me.
You promised me before the competition
that after the award ceremony,
we'd go to the Rocket Competition to find Wu Wei.
But you broke your promise.
You told me that day
that nothing mattered but being the champion.
I still remember it.
Whether it's rockets or the Math Olympiad,
they are both interesting to me.
But I just don't understand
why I have to be the champion.
What's the point of being the champion?
I've understood since then.
Everything in this world
doesn't have to be meaningful,
but it must be interesting.
But right now,
I don't know the purpose of my existence.
Why do I...
have to do something meaningful?
Wu Wei.
What took you so long?
You chickened out.
We agreed to enter the competition and win together.
What took you so long?
Is the championship that important?
Only winning is meaningful.
What's more important, winning or friends?
The championship is important.
How can you
think like that?
Auntie,
I don't think you're right.
My mom was just a regular worker who devoted her life
to the aerospace industry.
I chose aerospace as a career,
never for fame and fortune,
but for passion.
This passion of mine
may be because of my parents,
because of friends, because of childhood dreams,
but it's definitely not for titles, fame, or fortune.
Xiao Wu,
you're still young, you don't understand these things.
Auntie has been through this.
I'm doing all this for Ziqi's own good.
Auntie,
everyone in the space city
moves forward step by step
for their ideals and driven by their passion.
Many things cannot be measured by utility.
Passion itself is the meaning of passion.
Xiao Wu,
I think you misunderstood
what I meant.
Then since it's a passion,
you need success even more.
Right?
Auntie...
Stop talking.
Sorry, Auntie.
You guys keep talking.
Take care, Xiao Wu.
Mom, Dad,
it's getting late.
We still have work tomorrow.
Why don't you head back first?
Okay.
I won't be an eyesore here anymore.
I'll leave all these materials here for you.
Think about it when you have some free time.
The food I brought you,
your dad put it all in the fridge.
Remember,
you must eat eggs and drink milk in the morning.
And you must come home on weekends.
We asked Mr. Qin,
you're allowed to go out on weekends.
Come home and visit when you are free.
Come home.
Mr. Chen, wait for me.
Wait for me.
I chose aerospace as my career,
not for fame or wealth,
but for love.
This passion of mine
might be because of my parents,
my friends, or a childhood dream,
but definitely not for titles or fame.
Everyone in the Aerospace City
is here for their ideals.
Moving forward step by step with passion.
Many things can't be measured by utility.
Passion itself
is the meaning of passion.
The appointment is at nine, right?
Nan,
Do you think when they come with the plans later,
and we grade them,
they won't fight again, will they?
We've tried everything we could.
The rest is up to them.
No matter how they fight today,
we have to choose a plan today.
We can't delay it anymore.
You know,
if I also had top-tier skills,
that would be great.
If only I could have proposed a
more mature plan back then,
to balance things out,
they wouldn't be fighting.
All right, I don't blame you.
Let's not wait for them and start first.
You go first.
Both of you speak at the same time.
I thought about it last night.
Let's use your plan.
I also researched it yesterday.
My plan may indeed not be secure enough.
There are some steps I'm not confident about doing well.
All things considered,
Ying Ziqi's might be more reliable.
Are you sure you want to use my plan?
Don't force it.
I'm not forcing it.
Time is running out.
There's no need to argue anymore.
But if we use your plan,
we need to fully prepare all contingencies
to ensure the mission's success.
Since the pro has spoken,
let's just do it.
If Team Muxing is going to win, we win together.
If we lose, we lose together.
Let's get to work.
Muxing Team,
come on!
Control 1 reporting.
Longzhou 1 and Longgong 2
rendezvous and docking completed.
Both spacecraft attitudes and data are normal.
The first rendezvous and docking simulation flight control is finished.
Preparing for radial rendezvous and docking test.
It's our turn.
Control 3, please take over the command for the second docking test.
Leaders, experts,
we will now conduct
Muxing team's simulated flight control for rendezvous and docking.
Attention, all stations.
Perform the final check before simulated rendezvous and docking.
Control 2 copy.
The following parking point has been confirmed.
Control 5 copy.
The parking point data has been uploaded.
Control 4 copy.
Data monitoring is normal.
Unlike forward rendezvous and docking,
this radial docking
uses a bottom-up approach,
which is more difficult.
Control 4, attention.
Report at the relative distance node.
Control 4 reporting.
Longzhou-1 attitude is normal.
Longgong-2 attitude is normal.
The relative distance between the two
is 411.382 meters.
Relative speed is 0.45 meters per second.
Commencing radial pulse docking.
Control 5, copy.
Switching to the carrier camera feed.
Control 2, copy.
Docking mechanism getting ready.
Control 4 reporting.
Entering scheduled rendezvous and docking orbit.
Dragon Boat 1 attitude is normal.
Dragon Palace 2 attitude is normal.
Relative distance between the two spacecraft is 350 meters.
250 meters.
Preparing for automatic docking.
Control 3, copy that.
Control 4 reporting.
The two spacecraft are 200 meters apart.
Relative attitude is normal.
The distance between the two crafts is 150 meters.
The relative speed
hasn't slowed down.
Why is the relative speed still so fast?
Quick, get the contingency manual
and find a solution.
Here, here.
The manual.
Relative speed.
Look here.
The relative velocity.
Here.
In protocol 3112,
there is a command to adjust the relative velocity of the modules.
Relative velocity data is abnormal.
Control 3 requests protocol 3112.
Control 1 copies.
Approved to proceed with the protocol.
Control 3 requests manual docking.
Manual docking approved.
Attention, Control 4.
Execute protocol 3112.
Control 4 copies.
Control 4 executing protocol 3112.
Protocol 3112.
Control 4 reports.
Relative distance between modules is 100 meters.
Eighty meters.
Sixty meters.
Forty meters.
Twenty meters.
Muxing Team's
simulated flight control failed this time.
Let's carefully troubleshoot
every step.
Let's make a thorough summary.
Back to square one.
The satellite blew up, and Lao Qin will blow up too.
I remember my first simulated mission
was a launch and orbit simulation.
It was winter in Jiuquan.
The weather was terrible back then. It was freezing.
It was so cold that no matter what food we had,
it would get cold as soon as it was brought indoors.
There was a colleague in the thermal control team.
I still remember him very clearly to this day.
He was about your age,
maybe 27 or 28.
He was from Jiangnan.
This guy was extremely skilled
and especially loved to delve into research.
But because he was a southerner,
he really couldn't stand the cold of the Northwest.
He would just curl up like this.
That day, I don't know what he ate,
but he got an upset stomach.
He was tossing and rolling around in bed.
But even so, he persevered
and completed the task.
He said he had to hold on
because it was his first time.
After it was over,
there was a heavy snowstorm outside.
He grabbed the radio and ran out.
He was jumping, singing, and rolling in the snow.
And then, he never got up again.
I think if he had lived to this day,
some of you
might be his students.
He was young back then.
He also had a space dream.
But his first time
came to an abrupt end along with his life.
And what about you?
Your dreams have just begun.
I want you
to remember this moment.
Right now, the feeling of this very moment.
Remember it.
It will stay with you for the rest of your lives.
Mr. Qin.
Mr. Qin, can I say a few words?
You're out of breath from running.
Go ahead.
The failure of the newcomers' flight simulation this time
is completely my responsibility.
I didn't guide them well.
Actually, I've seen their plan.
It already showed signs of success.
It's a pity they were just a little short.
Since you've already seen signs of success,
it means they are starting to grow.
So it's fine.
You're not angry?
Why would I be angry?
Who would care for me if I got sick from anger?
Why did I go through so much trouble
to make them participate in this simulation task?
Because
surprise tests show the real level best.
Even if they fail,
it's meaningful to them.
Think about the beginning,
how you made it through.
This is a necessary path.
Mr. Qin,
rest assured.
We will work hard.
I believe in you.
What exactly went wrong?
The mission turned out like this.
I'll probably have to go back to the archives.
I wanted to do something big,
but I embarrassed myself this time.
This isn't our farewell dinner, is it?
Boys,
cherish it and don't lose heart.
The senior is quite nice,
treating us to snacks at a time like this.
This.
You're all here.
Come.
I bought this for you at my own expense.
Eat more. Eat enough this time.
Don't eat it anymore.
Why are you spacing out? You're not even eating.
Don't be discouraged. Keep it up.
Veggie bun.
Hurry up and eat.
You're as mad as a little toad.
It's fine.
You should also say less.
What does this mean?
Brother Wei.
Guilinggao means returning to zero.
They're saying our mission failed.
They want us to learn a lesson.
Didn't Lao Qin tell us
to always remember this day?
Weiwei.
Come out and eat.
Did you hear me, Weiwei?
Grandpa is calling you to eat.
Say something.
My parameters were just not accurate enough.
If you think they are wrong, you can tell me.
And how did you know
that was my final plan?
Just not accurate enough?
Wu Wei.
You work in aerospace.
In our industry,
there is no room for error.
Otherwise, it will be a catastrophic disaster.
And you are telling me it's just not accurate enough.
I am confident that this plan is foolproof.
And it better reflects our ideas.
The purpose of the mission
is to use the most reliable plan
to ensure the simulated flight control is completed smoothly,
not to show off.
Don't impose your personal goals
onto the team's mission.
Just having ideas
won't work.
What do you mean by that?
Choosing a better plan
and trying to prove my abilities and ideas...
Is that wrong?
You don't need to prove yourself.
You don't need to prove yourself,
not because you're so strong,
but because you just don't care.
Why did you come back without saying a word?
I mean,
did you mess up at work?
Hey, watch your mouth.
Watch your mouth.
What happened?
Tell Grandpa.
The simulation flight control we were in charge of failed.
I haven't even had time to share the good news.
I got into flight control,
and now I might have to go back to the archives.
I thought it was a big deal.
When your mom first did logistics at Aerospace City,
it wasn't smooth sailing either.
But she was never
as dejected as you.
She was always very motivated.
Dad.
What did I say back then?
Didn't I say he shouldn't go?
Said it was for some ideal, right?
You wanted to take a shortcut to the top.
You didn't make the shortcut.
You just crashed yourself.
I really don't understand.
What magic does this aerospace stuff have?
It makes your Wu family,
both young and old, follow each other blindly.
You never give up until it's too late.
You won't give up until you hit a brick wall.
That's exactly the style of our Wu family.
Once you set your mind on something,
you'll never give up easily.
If you do it, it's for a lifetime.
Not a minute or second less.
Seeing your stubbornness,
you really are like your mother.
You,
have always loved to copy her since childhood,
even loving aerospace.
If you ask me, if you hadn't done this,
you wouldn't be suffering now.
Are you done yet?
Fine.
I can't argue with you two.
All right, stop pulling a long face.
As a man,
everyone has difficulties and hurdles.
Let bygones be bygones.
It's no big deal.
Pick yourself up from where you fell.
Think about it.
Why were you named Wu Wei?
To be fearless.
Drink up.
Come on.
Didn't you say I couldn't drink?
Just listen to him.
Want a drink?
Come on.
All right, stop overthinking.
Exactly.
Mr. Qin.
Just you?
The flight simulation reset to zero.
Do you have anything to say?
I'm sorry, Mr. Qin.
I didn't do a good job this time.
Does this proposal reflect your true capability?
I personally recruited you.
But ever since you joined Space City,
you've been a huge disappointment.
I brought you here
because your abilities and experience
are above theirs.
I thought you could unite this team
and take charge.
I brought Wu Wei here
to stir things up.
But you can't just be a slacker forever.
Why did you come to Flight Control?
Why did you choose this major?
Think about it carefully.
I...
If...
If you are already
losing interest in this job,
have no passion,
and can't find a direction to strive for,
you don't have to wait until the internship ends.
You can leave right now.
Because you don't deserve to stay here.
Wu Wei.
Are you okay?
The simulated flight control mission failed.
Don't take it too hard.
It's a team mission.
Everyone is responsible for the failure.
I bought Ying Ziqi a cup.
Didn't his cup break last time?
So I bought him a new one.
Just give it to him yourself.
Just do me a favor and give it to him.
Please.
Let me just say one more thing.
I think you misunderstood Ying Ziqi.
The simulated flight control failed this time.
I think he's very upset too.
You don't need to make excuses for him.
I'm not making excuses for him.
If he wasn't upset,
he wouldn't have secretly reviewed it.
I think
he just doesn't want to show it in front of you.
Besides, for this mission,
you've already done a great job.
Come on.
I can't hear you.
This is for you.
Take it.
Don't go yet. Let me ask you something.
Am I really a wimp in your eyes?
Did you just realize that?
A wimp, a show-off,
and trying to run before I can walk.
You're right, Ying Ziqi.
We should have used your plan.
You don't need to take it all on yourself.
Wait a minute.
Tell me the truth.
Do you really think
I don't deserve to be in Flight Control,
or the Muxing Team?
Actually, during that rocket competition when we were kids,
I wasn't mad at you.
I was mad at myself.
If I had paid attention,
I could have finished the competition myself.
I might have even won the championship.
I thought...
I thought giving the championship to my mom
would make her better.
I was always getting into trouble back then.
I wasn't like you.
You were first in everything,
a model student,
the chosen one.
I never cared about being first.
But that one time,
I wanted to win.
I wanted my mom to be proud of me for once.
But when I wanted to win the most,
when I needed it the most,
I couldn't do it.
Do you remember when we were kids,
the wishes we made on the mountain?
None of them came true.
What did you wish for?
You, me, and Xiaoba,
will be good friends forever.
It won't come true if you say it out loud.
Then why did you ask me?
My turn.
To be good friends forever.
To win the rocket competition.
For Mom to get better.
Ying Ziqi,
Xiaoba, and I
will be good friends forever and ever.
Actually, I really envied you when we were kids.
Your mom always supported you
and never micromanaged you.
Yeah.
She supported me in everything.
Then again.
If you hadn't tricked me
into going to the Youth Palace when we were kids,
I wouldn't have become interested in aerospace,
let alone majored in it.
I owe all of this to you.
If it weren't for the rocket competition,
I wouldn't have fallen in love with aerospace.
But what's wrong with you?
I couldn't even get into this place,
yet you don't seem to care at all.
I just don't get it.
What exactly do you want to do?
I wish I knew.
I feel sick.
Is it wrong not to know?
I mean I feel sick.
Don't throw up on the floor.
Come on, let's go to the bathroom.
Slow down.
Don't throw up.
Actually, during that rocket competition when we were kids,
I wasn't mad at you.
I was mad at myself.
Muxing Team is amazing.
We are amazing.
Here, drink some water.
Wipe it.
No, don't.
Wrong way.
This way.
I feel so terrible.
Where is this?
I can't get up.
This way.
Bro.
The future depends on us.
Amazing.
If the future depends on you, we're doomed.
So annoying.
The Flight Control Center can't do without me.
Can't do without me.
Did you kick me yesterday?
Taking the opportunity for revenge. Is it fun?
Eat.
What else did you do?
You apologized to me.
I apologized to you? What do I owe you?
You said for the rocket competition when we were kids,
you shouldn't have blamed me.
That was ages ago.
That was drunk talk.
Don't take it seriously.
I didn't take it seriously.
Keep making it up.
Where are you going?
To work at the archives.
The names of spacecrafts and related missions in this series are fictionalized.
Ying Deqian, He Qiang
Chen Bing
Zhao Qiangjun
Wu Jianguo
Xiaobai
Wang Yiqi, Feng Shuaige, Tang Zixuan, Fu Jingyun, Wang Zhenglin, Qin Dehang, Zhang Haoming, Wang Zihan
Production Team
Life Producer Zhao Xuguang
Lighting Team
Gaffer
Sound Recordist
Painter
Production Staff
Hair and Makeup Team
Data Management Li Peiyuan, Tong Zhenzhong
Legal Team
Equipment Support
Beijing Liushun Huihuang Film & Television Media Co., Ltd.
Beijing Chuangxiang Xinshijie Film & Television Culture Co., Ltd.
Colorist
Visual Effects Production Company
Beijing Ziyou Xunhuan Digital Technology Co., Ltd.
VFX Supervisor Zhang Zheng
Beijing Moying Dongli Culture Media Co., Ltd.
Motion Graphic Designer
Compositor
Dubbing Production Team
Bianjiang Studio
Music Production Team
Theme Song 'Mu Xing'
Vocals
Lyricist
Poster Design Team
Special Thanks
Tianjin Xingye Real Estate Group Co., Ltd.
Tianjin Jingmao Metal Products Co., Ltd.
Publicity Department of the CPC Tianjin Nankai District Committee
Publicity Department of the CPC Tianjin Jinghai District Committee
Jingwumen Zhonghua Wulin Park
Jizhou Cheshenjia Scenic Area
Guiding Organization
News and Publicity Center of China National Space Administration
Zhengzhou New Power Film Co., Ltd.
Horgos New Power Film & Television Culture Co., Ltd.